Christian Rodriguez

Web Developer

l.aloeduardo@live.com.mx • +52 6181385346

https://www.linkedin.com/in/christianrp/ • https://github.com/ChristChampagne • http://christian-dev.tech/

Summary

 Passionate about IT, innovation and the latest technologies, I am a backend developer and a database administrator for both SQL and NoSQL databases. I have a solid 3-year track record in the industry, during which I have worked with a variety of mid to high-level programming languages, delivering powerful and effective solutions.

Skills

Python • JavaScript • PHP • Laravel • MySQL • MongoDB • React

Work Experience

Full Stack Developer

Jan 2023 - Apr 2023 • 3 mos

Toltekiani Tattoos • Part-time

Remote

Technologies: HTML/CSS • JavaScript • jQuery • PHP 7 • MySQL

• I spearheaded the creation of a robust advertising system that also functions as an appointment manager for Toltekiani Tattoos. This solution was aimed at enhancing information control and providing comprehensive tools for efficient scheduling. The implementation was carried out utilizing PHP with an MVC architecture, further augmented by the integration of design frameworks. This innovative approach greatly empowered the company's operations and information management capabilities.

Full Stack Developer Durango

Mar 2022 - Feb 2023 • 11 mos

Refacciones Victorino • Full-time

Durango, Mexico

Technologies: PHP • MVC • JavaScript • HTML/CSS • MySQL

Improved the automotive parts searching and selling by creating a manageable system. This system
allows the company to provide higher quality customer service and improve efficiency in the daily
workspace.

Full Stack Developer

Apr 2021 - Mar 2022 • 11 mos

Siempre Services

Remote

Technologies: Electron • JavaScript • HTML/CSS • MySQL • PHP

 I designed and implemented an advanced appointment and credential management system for Siempre Services, a global company specializing in tax and remittance management. This comprehensive system was developed using cutting-edge technologies, including PHP, and followed the MVC architectural pattern for optimal project organization and scalability.

Projects

<u>URL link Shortener</u>

Jan 2022 - Jan 2022 •

1 coworker

Technologies: JavaScript • PHP • MySQL • jQuery • HTML/CSS

I developed a tool capable of shortening large links into a small one helping people get to their landing pages quickly.

QR Code Generator Oct 2023 - Oct 2023 •

1 coworker

Technologies: JavaScript • HTML/CSS

I developed a QR code generator tool where people can enter the URL of a page to convert and scan it using their smartphone.

Educations

Bachelor's degree: Software Development

Sep 2022 - May 2023 • 8 mos

Universidad Tecnológica de Durango

Durango, Mexico Grade/GPA: 9.8

 Software Development & Management Engineer at Universidad Tecnológica de Durango, Durango, Durango 05/2023

Bachelor's degree : Técnico Superior Universitario en Tecnologías de la Información Apr 2020 - Sep 2022 • 2 yrs 5 mos

Universidad Tecnológica de Durango

Durango, Mexico Grade/GPA: 9.5

 Técnico Superior Universitario (T.S.U) Universidad Tecnológica de Durango, Durango 07/2022

Certifications & Awards

M001: MongoDB Basics - MongoDB University

Jan 2022

Languages

Spanish (Native or bilingual proficiency)

English (Full professional proficiency)